<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Entry on Vehicle Signal Specification</title>
    <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Entry on Vehicle Signal Specification</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 11:11:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Types</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/data_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 11:11:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/data_types/</guid>
      <description>Each data entry specifies a datatype from the following set (from Franca IDL). Datatypes shall not be used in branch entry
Supported datatypes    Name Type Min Max     uint8 unsigned 8-bit integer 0 255   int8 signed 8-bit integer -128 127   uint16 unsigned 16-bit integer 0 65535   int16 signed 16-bit integer -32768 32767   uint32 unsigned 32-bit integer 0 4294967295   int32 signed 32-bit integer -2147483648 2147483647   uint64 unsigned 64-bit integer 0 2^64 - 1   int64 signed 64-bit integer -2^63 2^63 - 1   boolean boolean value 0/false 1/true   float floating point number -3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Unit Types</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/data_unit_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 12:36:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/data_unit_types/</guid>
      <description>A signal can optionally specify a unit of measurement from the following set. This list composed with definition according to International Units (SI) and few automotive specific units: Specification, Wikipedia
   Unit type Domain Description     mm Distance Distance measured in millimeters   cm Distance Distance measured in centimeters   m Distance Distance measured in meters   km Distance Distance measured in kilometers   inch Distance Distance measured in inches   km/h Speed Speed measured in kilometers per hours   m/s Speed Speed measured in meters per second   m/s^2 Acceleration Acceleration measured in meters per second squared   cm/s^2 Acceleration Acceleration measured in centimeters per second squared   ml Volume Volume measured in milliliters   l Volume Volume measured in liters   cm^3 Volume Volume measured in cubic centimeters   celsius Temperature Temperature measured in degree celsius   degrees Angle Angle measured in degrees   degrees/s Angular Speed Angular speed measured in degrees per second   W Power Power measured in watts   kW Power Power measured in kilowatts   PS Power Power measured in horsepower   kWh Energy Consumption Energy consumption measured in kilowatt hours   g Weight Mass measured in grams   kg Weight Mass measured in kilograms   lbs Weight Mass measured in pounds   V Electric Potential Electric potential measured in volts   A Electric Current Electric current measured in amperes   Ah Electric Charge Electric charge measured in ampere hours   ms Time Time measured in milliseconds   s Time Time measured in seconds   min Time Time measured in minutes   h Time Time measured in hours   day Time Time measured in days   weeks Time Time measured in weeks   months Time Time measured in months   years Time Time measured in years   UNIX Timestamp Time Unix time is a system for describing a point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensors &amp; Actuators</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/sensor_actuator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 12:37:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/sensor_actuator/</guid>
      <description>Sensors are signals to read values of properties in a vehicle. Values of sensors typically change over time. Reading a sensor shall return the current actual value of the related property, e.g. the current speed or the current position of the seat.
Actuators are used to control the desired value of a property. Some properties in a vehicle cannot change instantly. A typical example is position of a seat or a window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributes</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 12:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/attributes/</guid>
      <description>An attribute is an entity that has a default value, specified by its default member. The standard Vehicle Signal Specification does not include default values for all attributes. If a default value has not been specified then the OEM must define a default value matching the actual vehicle. If the standard defines a default value but it does not fit the actual vehicle, then the OEM must override the standard default value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value restrictions</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/allowed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 12:37:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/rule_set/data_entry/allowed/</guid>
      <description>Specifying allowed values Optionally it is possible to define an array of allowed values, which will restrict the usage of the data entry in the implementation of the specification. It is expected, that any value not mentioned in the array is considered an error and the implementation of the specification shall react accordingly. The datatype of the array elements is the datatype defined for the data entry itself. For attributes it is possible to optionally set a default value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
