<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecosystem on Vehicle Signal Specification</title>
    <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecosystem on Vehicle Signal Specification</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 15:12:25 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Official VSS-Tools</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/tools/</guid>
      <description>VSS can be transformed into other formats or generated as code to integrate with other tooling environments and ecosystems.
The COVESA vss-tools project contains various helpful converters and is also used to validate the syntactic validity of the VSS standard catalogue.
If new features are introduced to the VSS specification, the community will ensure they are supported in the official vss-tools as well.
Fig 1. Generating various output formats from a VSS specification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Related Standards</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/standards/</guid>
      <description>Ohter standards or specifications sometimes reference VSS.
W3C VISS When using VSS in an automotive tech stack, a question is which protocols and technologies to use to access VSS signals.
The W3C Vehicle Information Service Specification (VISS) is an open standard, specifying a protocol to access VSS data via websocket (VISSv1, VISSv2) or HTTP/MQTT (VISSv2).
To learn more check
Vehicle Information Service Specification (VISS) V1 published as a Discontinued Draft. Vehicle Information Service Specification (VISS) V2, feature complete and in process to enter the Candidate Recommendation stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software &amp; Solutions</title>
      <link>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/ecosystem/software/</guid>
      <description>Various software frameworks and products exist to work with VSS data. Some are Open Source, some are commercial prducts and services. There are solutions to work with VSS in-vehicle, as well as using it in the cloud.
The best entry-point for an up-to-date introduction to VSS products and Use Cases is the COVESA VSS wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
